SAM MACINTYRE

I'm a skilled, creative graphic designer who loves working with brands to design stand out packaging & engaging visual experiences.

An inquisitive problem solver, my experience ranges from concept & brand development, through to packaging development & overall project management. I successfully drive projects from concept to completion whilst producing high quality, creative designs along the way working with some of the biggest names in food, drinks & retail around the world.

GET IN TOUCH

+61 (0) 455 206 087

hello@sammacintyre.com linkedin.com/in/sammacintyre

PORTFOLIO

sammacintyre.com

EXPERIENCE

Packaging Graphic Designer

Target Australia, Retail, target.com.au

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Melbourne, Australia

- Successfully managed the roll out of own brand beauty packaging redesign, building out the style guide and artwork templates across various pack formats and providing art direction and management of internal stakeholder approvals for upwards of 250 SKUs across 6 local suppliers.
- Simplified Main Range sew-in labels, resulting in consistency in size and colour across all apparel departments, and reducing label job numbers in the system by 90% allowing for more efficient allocation to products and cost savings when forecasting.
- Refreshed MAXX brand packaging in the children's underwear and sleep and extended packaging artwork into socks contributing to 75% increase in department sales vs LY.

Freelance Graphic Designer

Various Clients - Examples below

Mar. 2019 - Jan. 2020

Melbourne, Australia

- APR Creative Creative Agency, aprcreative.com.au

 Regular freelance support across everything from packaging concept development, print layout design, creation of digital assets & motion graphics.
- The Animals Creative Ad Agency, theanimals.com.au Creation & roll-out of key visuals across print & digital.
- Moose Toys Toy Industry, moosetoys.com/au
 Assisted packaging concept development for Treasure X Fire vs Ice & Treasure X Aliens.

Graphic Designer

Mar. 2016 - Dec. 2018

Lightbody Ventures, Food Industry, lightbodyventures.com

Glasgow, UK

- Was brand guardian for all packaging and sales support material for the \$15m Hershey Company licensed bakery product range in the USA. I designed all artwork and managed approvals with Hershey to ensure everything adhered to their strict brand quidelines.
- Designed packaging for Disney Kitchen toddler snacking range, contributing to attainment of Mumsnet Rated license (a first for the toddler snacking category) and The Grocer New Product Award for "Apple Fruity Bakes".
- Introduced artwork sign off procedure to ensure output was 100% accurate and had always been sighted by the appropriate parties before going to print.

1

EXPERIENCE

Packaging Technologist

Sep. 2015 - Mar. 2016

Beam Suntory UK Ltd, Whisky Industry, beamsuntory.com

Glasgow, UK

- Identified inconsistencies in typesetting across Laphroaig Lore packaging. Organised meetings between the separate agencies working on the packaging to ensure text was consistent across all SKUs.
- Organised bottling line trial for Laphroaig Lore, the outcome of which allowed critical decisions to be made on the pack format and the project to be delivered on time.
- Coordinated early supplier meetings and built out packaging development critical paths, assisting in the successful delivery of the high value Black Bowmore 50 Year Old whisky - worth 16,000 per bottle.

Product Designer

Oct. 2014 - Jul. 2015

Worlds Apart (now Moose Toys UK), Children's Products

Newquay, UK

 Designed artwork using licensed style guides for various children's products including pop-up tents and ReadyBed® blow up beds. Licenses worked with included Disney Frozen, Despicable Me & Paw Patrol.

EDUCATION

MEng (Hons) Product Design Engineering, 2:1

University of Glasgow / The Glasgow School of Art